{
    "id": "16d3271843cf48b7978fa2f6d7a011fd",
    "title": "Questions And Negatives Exercise",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "d000346b712f4afab546553b1747f440",
            "title": "Questions And Negatives",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "She …………………. want to be disturbed while she is working.",
                    "description": "In the simple present tense, we make negatives by putting do not or does not before the infinitive. We use does not when the subject is a singular noun or pronoun.",
                    "answers": [
                        "does not",
                        "do not",
                        "has not"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "You ………………… returned the camera you borrowed from me.",
                    "description": "The past participle 'returned' clearly indicates that we need have, not do, here.",
                    "answers": [
                        "has not",
                        "did not",
                        "have not"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "Michael ………………… speak French.",
                    "description": "We use ‘does not’ here because Michael is a singular noun.",
                    "answers": [
                        "do not",
                        "does not",
                        "has not"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "Did you ………………. the parcel last week?",
                    "description": "After do and does we use the infinitive (first form of the verb). Did + send -> sent",
                    "answers": [
                        "sent",
                        "send"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "They ……………….. the meeting yesterday.",
                    "description": "The present perfect tense cannot be used with past time expressions.",
                    "answers": [
                        "didn't attend",
                        "haven't attended",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "She buys a lot of things she ………………",
                    "description": "We use does with singular nouns and pronouns. Also, we use the simple present to talk about habits. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "do not want",
                        "does not want",
                        "has not wanted"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "…………………. you injure yourself while playing football yesterday?",
                    "description": "The auxiliaries do and have are used in the present tenses. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "Do",
                        "Did",
                        "Have"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "Where could .....................… at this hour of the night?",
                    "description": "In questions, only the first of the two auxiliaries goes before the subject.",
                    "answers": [
                        "have she gone",
                        "she have gone",
                        "she have went"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "……………… I told you not to be late?",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "Didn't",
                        "Haven't",
                        "Don’t"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "They …………………. tabulated the marks yet.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "did not",
                        "have not",
                        "do not"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "Have you been ………………. for long?",
                    "description": "In the present perfect continuous tense, we use has/have + been + ing form of the verb.",
                    "answers": [
                        "wait",
                        "waiting",
                        "waited"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "Rahul ………………. the test in the first attempt.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "did not pass",
                        "has not pass",
                        "does not pass"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}